<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<experience>
  <research>
    <title>Computational Aspect of Spike Neural Network</title>
    <advisor>Dr. Kai-Min Chung, Dr. Chi-Yen Lu</advisor>
    <abstract>In this work, we focused on the integrate-and-fire model, which has been widely used and studied in the society of neuron science. Instead of studying the properties and feasibilities of the model, we examined the intrinsic computational aspect of SNN and tried to identify the underlying computational problem SNN is solving. Motivated by some works in neuron science which indicated that SNN is heuristically solving certain quadratic programming problem with parameters encoded in their network structure. We proved that SNN is indeed solving a linear system problem and derived convergence rate. Furthermore, we observed that in our simulation, the coefficients produced by SNN were usually small. As a result, we conjectured that SNN is not only solving a linear system, but also finding the smallest feasible solution, i.e. the \(\ell_1\) minimization problem.</abstract>
    <docname>Technical Report</docname>
    <doclink>cnchou_research_computational_tradeoff.pdf</doclink>
  </research>

  <research>
    <title>Computational and Statistical Tradeoff in Graphical Problems</title>
    <advisor>Professor I-Hsiang Wang</advisor>
    <abstract>Empty</abstract>
    <docname>Technical Report</docname>
    <doclink>cnchou_research_computational_tradeoff.pdf</doclink>
  </research>

  <research>
    <title>Estimating and Testing the Number of Components in Stochastic Mixture Models</title>
    <advisor>Professor I-Hsiang Wang</advisor>
    <abstract>Empty</abstract>
    <docname>Technical Report</docname>
    <doclink>cnchou_research_mixture.pdf</doclink>
  </research>

  <research>
    <title>Dynamic Difficulty Scheme in Bitcoin</title>
    <advisor>Advisor: Professor Professor Shih-Wei Liao, Dr. I-Ping Tu</advisor>
    <abstract>Empty</abstract>
    <docname>Manuscript</docname>
    <doclink>cnchou_research_bitcoin.pdf</doclink>
  </research>
</experience>

